Guide to the JoAnn Evansgardner and Gerald H.F. Gardner Papers, 1965-1991 AIS.2001.09
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Legal Topics, VIII.
  - Equal Rights Act, 1.
    - Permission Forms, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania Campaign, 1973-1978 (Box 24, Folder 03-04)
    - Professional Women's Caucus, 1970 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - ERA and Religion, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Richmond Bus, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Missouri NOW ERA Lawsuit, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Campaign at State Levels, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 09-10)
    - Social Action, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Social Security, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Supporters, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Unions, 1974 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Oklahoma Campaign, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Equal Rights, 1968-1970 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Ratification Groups, 1968-1972 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - May 7th Demonstration, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - March on the Post Office, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - July 9th Demonstration, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Sex Discrimination in the Work Place, 2.
    Sex discrimination in the workplace, specifically in job advertisements, hiring, and actual positions held once hired, was a particular interest of Evansgardner and Gardner and they participated in several court cases surrounding these issues. Most notable are NOW v. Pittsburgh Press, Cease v. A & P, Weeks v. Bell, and Sharon Johnson v. University of Pittsburgh. NOW v. Pittsburgh Press was a court case in the early 1970's dealing with sex discrimination in want ads. NOW fought to compel the Pittsburgh Press to eliminate discriminatory headings because want ads were being published under headings listing gender qualifications and, within these headings, were stereotypical job ads. For example, technical jobs were listed under the "Male" heading while clerical jobs were listed under the "Female" heading. On the rare occasion that a job was listed under both headings, there were significant differences in pay scales. Cease v. A & P and Weeks v. Bell were two cases, also in the 1970's, in which women were being discriminated against after they were hired. The two companies were discriminating in the areas of: job classification, compensation, seniority, promotions, scheduling and overtime, benefits and terms and conditions of employment. Sharon Johnson v. University of Pittsburgh was a case in the 1970's concerning the issue of tenure denial based on gender. This subseries includes research, correspondence, laws, ordinances and guidelines, press, and statements and positions.
    - Correspondence and Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Reports on the Division of Employment Advertisements Based on Sex, 1969-1970 (Box 24, Folder 22-27)
    - Pittsburgh Press Correspondence and Clippings, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Pitt News Announcement and Advertisements, 1969 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Clippings- Employment Discrimination Based on Sex, 1969-1972 (Box 24, Folder 30-33)
    - New York Times Clippings, 1971-1975 (Box 24, Folder 34-35)
    - Clippings- Employment Discrimination Based on Sex, 1969-1972 (Box 25, Folder 01-05)
    - Documentation, Correspondence and Articles about Sex Discrimination in Want Ads, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 06-10)
    - Female Government Employee Studies, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 11-13)
    - Bendix Field Engineering Corporation, Correspondence, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Letters to Local Corporations Who Place Help Wanted Ads, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Gerry Gardner to the Editor of the Pittsburgh Press, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission to Pennsylvania Governor, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Letters to Pittsburgh Press, 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Gerry Gardner to University of Pittsburgh, 1969-1973 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Want-Ad Segregation across U.S., 1973-1974 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Ordinances and Guidelines, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Pittsburgh Ordinance, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Case Judgment, 1971 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Supreme Court and Commonwealth Court of Pennsylvania Decision, 1971-1973 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Common Pleas Court of Allegheny County Decision, 1971-1972 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Human Relations Ordinances, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Employment Discrimination Ordinances from Other Cities, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 27-28)
    - Legislation, 1965-1970 (Box 25, Folder 29-31)
    - Sex Discrimination, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - U.S. House Bills and Petitions, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - History of Pittsburgh Press Case, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Demonstration Handout, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence and Clippings Concerning Case, 1969-1972 (Box 26, Folder 05-10)
    - Pittsburgh Press Exhibit, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Gerald H.F. Gardner Law Correspondence and Statements, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - EEOC Guidelines, 1967-1969 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - NOW Report to the Human Relations Commission, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Legal correspondence and Petitions, 1972-1977 (Box 26, Folder 15-20)
    - A & P Seniority Lists, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Mailing Lists, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Phone Lists, undated (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Pamphlets, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Records of Meetings, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence Regarding Case, 1972-1978 (Box 26, Folder 26-29)
    - Clippings and Newsletters, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Case Notes, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - CEASE Public Relations, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - PHRC Reports and Correspondence, 1978 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Legal Documents, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - National Labor Relations Board, undated (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Equal Employment Study, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Federal Contract Compliance Orders, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - EEOC v. AT&T, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 03-04)
    - AT&T Rates and Employment for Pittsburgh, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Case Statement, Bell Telephone, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Supervisors Training, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Action Coordinators, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Helen Reig Correspondence, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - George Sape Correspondence, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Case Planning Notes, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Protest Mailings, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - NOW Plan for Case, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Documents, Correspondence, and Memos, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Decision, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Press Releases ,1971 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1971-1973 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - NOW Chapter Actions, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Bell Telephone Company of PA, 1971-1974 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Telephone Rate Structure Report, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Affirmation Action Plan for SW PA Bell, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Utility Complaint Forms, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and Settlement Documents, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - PHRC v. Rueben H. Donnelly Corporation and Bell Telephone, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - NOW against Phone Company Discrimination, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Bell Affirmation Action Model Plan, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Statement, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - AT&T Information, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Nelson, Bell Telephone Co. Conciliation Agreement, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Legal Documents, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Court Records, 1973-1977 (Box 27, Folder 31-32)
    - Heinz Letter for Sharon Johnson, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence and Clippings, 1971-1977 (Box 27, Folder 34-38)
    - Ina Braden, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Hew Clippings, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Committee for Affirmative Action in Universities, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - EEOC and PHRC, 3.
    The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) and the Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission (PHRC) are two organizations that work to eliminate discrimination based on sex, color, race, or religion. When a person has a complaint toward an employer or other individual, these organizations work to investigate the charge. If it is determined that discrimination did, in fact, occur, it is the responsibility of these associations to enforce antidiscrimination laws. While the EEOC works on the federal level, complaints must be reviewed by local organizations before they can legally conduct their own investigations. In the early 1970s, NOW accused PHRC of improperly handling investigations, encouraging complainants to accept lower results, and discriminating against its own employees. As a result of this accusation, an appeal to investigate PHRC was presented to Governor Thornburgh. This subseries includes general information, complaints, and information relating to the investigation of PHRC.
    - Women's Labor Law (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence/Articles, 1969-1976 (Box 28, Folder 01-02)
    - Carswell Nomination Statement, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Female Employment Statistics, 1970-1974 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - PA NOW and Employment Discrimination, 1970-1973 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Job Rights for Women in Pennsylvania, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Available Positions, Pittsburgh Area Businesses, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Corporate Advertisements from GE and Quality Inn, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Employment Clippings, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Allegheny county Budget and Employment Stats, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 11-13)
    - Affirmative Enforcement Project and Affirmative Response Employment, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Affirmative Action, Duquesne Light, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Pittsburgh Press, Employment Advertisement Dispute, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Changes to Labor Laws since 1966, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Publications and Reports, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Federal Equality Laws, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - NOW and Employment Discrimination, 1972-1978 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Press Release, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Laws about EEOC, 1964-1972 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Compliance Workshop Kit, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - Gardner v. EEOC, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 24-25)
    - Letters of Complaints, 1972-1973 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - Newsletter, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - EEOC Jobs, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 29-30)
    - Rapid Charge Processing Manual, undated (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - Supreme Court Decisions, 1974 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - EEOC Symposium, 1976 (Box 28, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973-1975 (Box 28, Folder 34)
    - Reports, 1972-1974 (Box 28, Folder 35)
    - Bill Brock, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 36)
    - Affirmative Action Program, 1972 (Box 28, Folder 37)
    - News Release, 1973 (Box 28, Folder 38)
    - PHRC Bill of Rights, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Staff Bulletin and Civil Service Act, 1976-1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Committee Meeting Minutes, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 03-04)
    - Training Program, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Contract Compliance Program, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Pattern and Practice Committee, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Letters, Testimonies, and Pamphlets, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 08-09)
    - Projects and Reports, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Pittsburgh Human Relations Council, 1965-1972 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - PA State Human Relations, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Sears Roebuck and Co., 1971 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - List of PHRC Complaints, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Pittsburgh Cases Based on Sex, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - PHRC v. Nabisco, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Mrs. Celeste R. Humphries, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Crystal Newcomer, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Dixie White, President of NOW, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Mary Grom, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - Margaret Martin, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 21-22)
    - Bill of Rights for Complainants to the PHRC, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Rev. Donald W. McIlvane, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - PHRC v. Thorp, Reed, and Armstrong, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - PHRC v. City of Beaver Falls, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - New Sex Amendment to PHRC Act, undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - Statement- NOW to the Commissioner's of the PHRC, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Information on NOW wanting Investigation of PHRC, undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - Gerald Gardner's Drafts of Statements, undated (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - James Simms Correspondence, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - Attacks on PHRC Clippings, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - Evansgardner Interview for Position and PHRC, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - PHRC Committee Members, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - PHRC Affirmative Action/Equal Employment Opportunity Policy Statement, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - PHRC Presentation by Joann Evansgardner, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - Commissioners Meeting, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 37-38)
    - Plan of Action for Proposed PHRC Committee: Phase One, undated (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - NOW/PHRC Executive Committee, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - Letter to Governor Shapp, undated (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Other Legal Concerns, 4.
    NOW and Evansgardner were interested in all types of sex discrimination and did not limit themselves to discrimination in the workplace. They corresponded with several individuals and provided support and suggestions in a variety of situations, including sex discrimination in the public schools. They also kept current with court cases and laws and opinions related to sex discrimination throughout the 1970's. Evansgardner also participated in several of her own court cases. After PHRC awarded a position she had applied for to a less qualified male candidate, Evansgardner accused the commission of sex discrimination. This subseries includes materials relating to legal disputes within NOW, court documents, correspondence, photos, and legal documents such as bills and orders.
    - Murphy's Negotiations, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - Court Decisions, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - Miscellaneous, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - Complainants Seeking Help from NOW, undated (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - Bakke Case- Clippings, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - NOW Lawsuits Against Various Organizations, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - Eleanor Smeal, et al v. NOW, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - NOW and Karen Secrest v. PA Bureau of Employment Security, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - NOW in Various Cases, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - Supreme Court Cases Involving NOW and Evansgardner, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 51-52)
    - Evansgardner v. Westinghouse (Box 30, Folder 01-03)
    - Compliance Letter, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - NOW Agreement with Westinghouse Broadcasting Co., Inc., undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Pennsylvania State Board of Education, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - NOW Lawsuits, 1980-1981; 1986 (Box 30, Folder 07-08)
    - Photos of Evansgardner and Mayor Caliguiri, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Port Authority of Allegheny County Lawsuits, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 11-12)
    - Brown v. Brown, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - JoAnn Evansgardner's Complaint Against Pittsburgh District Office, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Evansgardner and the EEOC, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Evansgardner's Sex Discrimination Case, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - Compliance Monthly Report, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Jameson v. TWA, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Margaret A. Harris v. Civil Service Commission for Allegheny Police and Firemen, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Oskoui vs. University of Pittsburgh; Sanday v. CMU, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 20-21)
    - Jo Samuel v. University of Pittsburgh, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Court Decisions, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Sandra Wetzel and Mari Ross v. Liberty Mutual Insurance Co., 1975 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Prandini v. National Tea Company, 1975-1976 (Box 30, Folder 25-26)
    - Commonwealth Court Decision on Interrogatories, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Commonwealth of Pa., et al v. Peter Flaherty, 1976 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Phyllis M. Cropp v. Allegheny Ludlum Industries, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Mary Grom v. The Great Atlantic and Pacific Tea Company, Inc., 1977 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Student committee to Defend Dr. Paul Nyden, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Mary Sacriponte Arbitration Case, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Rostker v. Goldberg, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Supreme Court Case on Women's Rights and Civil Rights, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - House Bills, 1969-1972 (Box 30, Folder 35-36)
    - Williams Bill Title VII, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Pennsylvania Court Opinions about Discrimination, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Revised Order #4, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Ordinance 75, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Suburb Ruling and Petition, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Louise A. Taylor Grievance, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Harriet Schwartz and Bonnie Price Complaint, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - House Bill 678, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Senate Bill no. 321, 1979 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Commission for Responsive Democracy, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 10)
- Research Topics/Subject Files, IX.
  Evansgardner and Gardner kept extensive research files on many feminist and other issues, as well as a card catalog of possible resources such as books, journals, and names and phone numbers of contacts. These files provide more detail and background information and are most helpful when used in conjunction with other series. With the exception of documents relating to Black Feminism and Male Feminism, which have their own sections, files are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Draft of Gardner Speech on Basics of Feminism, undated (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Women's Project Report, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Reports on Various Women's Issues, 1969-1973 (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
  - Reports on Equal Rights, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Women's Conference Study, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Activism, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Women Management, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Directories of Businesses Owned by Women and Minorities, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Collection of Information on Women's Issues, 1978 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Women in Insurance Industry, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Professional Opportunities for Women, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Feminist Ideology, 1971-1974 (Box 31, Folder 24-25)
  - Black Feminism
  - Attempt to Eliminate Affirmative Action, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Black Women in Women's Movement, 1967; 1970 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Minority and Women's Rights Questionnaire, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Journal- Black Women (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Black Feminist Conference, 1972; 1976 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Black Feminist Conference, 1972; 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Black Women's Association, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Black Women Biography, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Books for Black Women, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Black Economists, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Racism Memos, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Krystal Brent Zook, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Journals on Women and Racial Issues, 1974-1979 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Ruth Frankenburg, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Male Feminism
  - Male and Female Readings, 1973-1977 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Sexism and Men, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Kansas City Male Feminists, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Male Liberation, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Male Feminism Fliers, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Male Feminism Articles, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Feminism Fact sheets, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Men's Feminism Guide, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Intelligent Man's Guide to Feminism, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Feminism Workshop for Men, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Double F, A Magazine on Male Effeminism, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Men's Collective Conference, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Male Questionnaire, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Racism
  - Black Consumer Market, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Black Power, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Born to be Unemployed, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Civil Rights and Communities Journals, 1967-1973 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Combating Racism Kit, 1984 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Eliminating Racism Workshop, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Eliminating Racism, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Ethnic Issues, 1966-1970 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Institutional Racism, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Institutional Racism Fact Sheets, 1973-1979 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - McIntosh, Peggy, 1988-1992 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Index of Militancy, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 35)
  - The Militant, 1969 (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - Report of the Minority Rights Group, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - NAACP, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - Prejudice Report, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - Psychology and Racism in Society, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - Psychological Effects of Racism, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 41)
  - Racial Issues Clippings, 1973-1979 (Box 32, Folder 42)
  - South Hills Association for Racial Equality, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 43)
  - U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 44)
  - Wetherby, Phyllis, undated (Box 32, Folder 45)
  - YWCA, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 46)
  - Subject Files
  - Abortion, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Age Discrimination, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - American Council on Education, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Beauty Contests- Clippings (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Bell Telephone, 1969, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Carolyn Shaw Bell, 1973 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Berman, Edgar, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Jessie Bernard, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Birth Control, 1969-1970 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Nancy Boweller Campaign, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Brazil, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Business and Professional Women, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Business Ownership Among Women, undated (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Canadian Commission on Women, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Carter, Angela, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - Cattel's Memorial, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - Changing Discrimination (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Chancellor Posvar, August 1975 (Box 33, Folder 18)
  - Chatham Conference, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 19)
  - Child Care, 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 20)
  - Children's Literature, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 21)
  - Civil Rights Memos, 1970's (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Clippings (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Clinical Child Psychology, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Clothing Styles, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Colgate Campaign, undated (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Common Cause, undated (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - Communes, undated (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - Community College Handouts, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - Connections Newsletter, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - Consciousness Raising and Small Groups, 1971-1973 (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - Cooper for Senate, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - Co-op, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - Corporations and Computerization (Box 33, Folder 35)
  - Counseling, 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 36)
  - Credit, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence, Phyllis M. Cropp, June 21, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence, Dickler, Florence, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 39)
  - Davis, Angela, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 40)
  - Discrimination in Education, 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 41)
  - Discrimination Memorandums, 1974-1978 (Box 33, Folder 42)
  - Divorce Laws (Box 33, Folder 43)
  - Draft, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 44)
  - Economics of Women's Place, 1968 (Box 33, Folder 45)
  - Economic Proprieties Report, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 46)
  - EEOC, 1970-1971 (Box 33, Folder 47)
  - Elementary School, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 48)
  - Employment, 1967-1971 (Box 33, Folder 49-50)
  - Encounter Groups, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 51)